<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Akhil Pandey</title>
    <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Akhil Pandey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://akhilpandey95.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Present, the paradox of inexistance coupled with reality</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/present-the-paradox-of-inexistance-coupled-with-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/present-the-paradox-of-inexistance-coupled-with-reality/</guid>
      <description>As a child, I always played this wonderful yet silly game where I asked someone to point out or show me present and I used to say well that is not present anymore.
The idea of present The culmination of thought and reality in our</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>conceptNet - A new proposition for interpreting deep learning models</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/conceptnet---a-new-proposition-for-interpreting-deep-learning-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/conceptnet---a-new-proposition-for-interpreting-deep-learning-models/</guid>
      <description>Interpretability is one of the important problems of this century</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligence, that which deep learning models do not have</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/intelligence-that-which-deep-learning-models-do-not-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/intelligence-that-which-deep-learning-models-do-not-have/</guid>
      <description>The measure of intelligence is a wonderful article</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On thesis, the journey of master&#39;s study and Ph.D</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/on-thesis-the-journey-of-masters-study-and-ph.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/on-thesis-the-journey-of-masters-study-and-ph.d/</guid>
      <description>I recently defended my thesis titled, &amp;lsquo;Using machine learning models to discover promising research&amp;rsquo;.The hypothesis here is to understand</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using metal backend for training deep learning architectures</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/using-metal-backend-for-training-deep-learning-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/using-metal-backend-for-training-deep-learning-architectures/</guid>
      <description> In order to take advantage of the AMD GPU’s for running memory intensive programs on a device running macOS Training a deep learning model
Some jargon that might be helpful  cupy: It is numpy library that supports operation on a CUDA GPU. pyopenCL: It is an OpenCL implementation of the library pyopenGL.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding topic modelling with the help of deep learning models</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/understanding-topic-modelling-with-the-help-of-deep-learning-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/understanding-topic-modelling-with-the-help-of-deep-learning-models/</guid>
      <description>When we are trying to have a conversation with another person we inadvertently try to extract the concepts or topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling about random things</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/rambling-about-random-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/rambling-about-random-things/</guid>
      <description> I sometimes wonder if the desire to question the fundamental nature of things is somewhat too a
On conventions On education On language On relationships On conversations On philosophy On philology On childhood On responsibility On coherence On influence On movies </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Atlanta using Relay</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/understanding-atlanta-using-relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/understanding-atlanta-using-relay/</guid>
      <description>Group project are always fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural networks a mathematical understanding about the concept</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/neural-networks-a-mathematical-understanding-about-the-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/neural-networks-a-mathematical-understanding-about-the-concept/</guid>
      <description>Neural networks are a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising daily commute with geo spatial data</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/visualising-daily-commute-with-geo-spatial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/visualising-daily-commute-with-geo-spatial-data/</guid>
      <description>In an effort to build visualisations for a course project I ended up discovering interesting findings from my day to day commute to college. To give more context into</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequence to sequence neural attention model for text summarisation</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/sequence-to-sequence-neural-attention-model-for-text-summarisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/sequence-to-sequence-neural-attention-model-for-text-summarisation/</guid>
      <description>Facebook published a research paper that presented an interesting proposition about having a neural attention model for sentence summarisation. The paper was authored by Alexander M. Rush, Sumit Chopra, Jason Weston</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building word embedding based models with</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/building-word-embedding-based-models-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/building-word-embedding-based-models-with/</guid>
      <description>fastText is a open source library that uses a neural network architecture creating word embeddings for text. It uses bag of n-grams instead of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signalling theory and its application on one’s own ethos</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/signalling-theory-and-its-application-on-ones-own-ethos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/signalling-theory-and-its-application-on-ones-own-ethos/</guid>
      <description>What is signalling theory ? It is concept in evolutionary biology that focusses on understanding the relationship between the signals given by species and how they are understood by other species. The specific concept I am interested to talk in this blog post is about zahavian signals.
What is a Zahavian Signal ? Amotz Zahavi, an Israeli evolutionary biologist best known for his work about handicap principle talks about cost signalling in which he describes that for a signal to be honest it has to be costly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morality - it&#39;s influence on thought and action</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/morality---its-influence-on-thought-and-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/morality---its-influence-on-thought-and-action/</guid>
      <description>I am not a philosopher but I observe the fundamental nature of things in my surroundings. Right from my childhood to this moment when I am orchestrating this article there are countless thoughts that surround my head when my inner self whispers “morality”. My thought process takes quick writhing movements wandering around searching for answers. The reason for me writing this piece is to both look for answers and portray my ethos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three C&#39;s of Javascript</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/the-three-cs-of-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/the-three-cs-of-javascript/</guid>
      <description>You might be wondering what the three C’s are :
 Currying Closures Callbacks  Ok what are those ?
Before I start, let me tell you that in Javascript Functions are Objects. So every object in Javascript, be it Number, String, Array; Every Object in javascript has a prototype object. For instance if the object is declared using an object literal then, it has access to Object.prototype, Similarly all the arrays so declared have access to the Array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>numgo - ND Array based math library for Go</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/numgo---nd-array-based-math-library-for-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/numgo---nd-array-based-math-library-for-go/</guid>
      <description>numgo - ND Array based math library for Go Mathematical computations and statistical operations contribute immensely to the development of machine learning models in diverse disciplines. Arrays are the most frequently used data structure in most of these applications. Basing on this I have thought of porting python’s numpy library to go-lang. The name of the project is numgo. After learning go-lang I always wanted to practically implement something with the knowledge I have gathered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pubundsci - An independent research study</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/pubundsci---an-independent-research-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/pubundsci---an-independent-research-study/</guid>
      <description>While technological and scientific advancement paved its way in the 20th century giving scope for researchers to publish of a plethora of scientific literature, “Public Understanding of Science” has been at the center stage of discussion among researchers for the past decade. This very concern sprouts from the fact that most of the scientific reportage that occurs on News Media is subject to personal interpretation. Also, the misapprehensions of the scientific findings can cause repercussions of unimaginable scale in the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compatibility for the Web</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/compatibility-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/compatibility-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Webcompat, is one of the recent interests that I find myself occupied with. The community is wonderful and the whole idea of having a place where users can report problems is quite fantastic. I believe that this can evolve as something greater, since webcompat.com is not only a website that focusses on bug reporting and problems, since I believe that it is a common ecosystem where users, developers and site owners are notified with the issues on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the GNU/Linux System</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/tuning-the-gnu/linux-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/blog/tuning-the-gnu/linux-system/</guid>
      <description>I always used to find myself in a difficult situation when I had to travel and work. The main reason for this is my machine had a GNU/Linux based distro running and I couldn’t stay away from a charging spot for more than two hours. I always was intrigued to explore this segment and solve this very problem in order to better my travel experience. Basically there are couple of things to be kept in mind before you go out and try the tricks mentioned here, Consider them basics; So they are : * The Kernel plays a major role in providing support to enhance battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LearnJs</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/learnjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/learnjs/</guid>
      <description>A Javascript cheatsheet for beginners. The project explains about Javascript and its functionalities with short examples. It is an attempt to portray the best parts of Javascript that are pretty tough and hard to find. It is a congregation of best practices, language constructs, and other simple yet effective snippets that gives us an essence of how we can harness the best out of the language</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>altpred</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/altpred/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/altpred/</guid>
      <description>An independent study trying to understand the relationship between scholarly articles and social media reference indicators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>m.bot</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/m.bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/m.bot/</guid>
      <description>A conversation AI that would be assisting researchers to gain scholarly insights. It analyzing documents, extracts information from images and answers questions based on the knowledge acquired.(under-development)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pubudnsci</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/pubundsci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/pubundsci/</guid>
      <description>An independent study examining the effects of public understanding of scientific literature on real world. The core idea is to mathematically frame the relationship between scientific literature and the its impact on general public and use machine learning models to prove the established hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reproducibility</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/reproducibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.com/projects/reproducibility/</guid>
      <description>An independent study focussing on understanding the aspect of reproducibility in research papers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>