<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Akhil Pandey</title>
    <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Akhil Pandey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.136.5</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://akhilpandey95.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Landscape of Reproducible Research: A Predictive Modeling Approach</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/repropredmodeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/repropredmodeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reproducibility of scientific articles is central to the advancement of science. Despite this importance, evaluating reproducibility remains challenging due to the scarcity of ground truth data. Predictive models can address this limitation by streamlining the tedious evaluation process. Typically, a paper&amp;rsquo;s reproducibility is inferred based on the availability of artifacts such as code, data, or supplemental information, often without extensive empirical investigation. To address these issues, we utilized artifacts of papers as fundamental units to develop a novel, dual-spectrum framework that focuses on author-centric and external-agent perspectives. We used the author-centric spectrum, followed by the external-agent spectrum, to guide a structured, model-based approach to quantify and assess reproducibility. We explored the interdependencies between different factors influencing reproducibility and found that linguistic features such as readability and lexical diversity are strongly correlated with papers achieving the highest statuses on both spectrums. Our work provides a model-driven pathway for evaluating the reproducibility of scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Reproducibility on Scientific Impact</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/influencerepro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/influencerepro/</guid>
      <description>ICSSI&amp;#39;24 Best Poster Award</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility Signals in Science: A preliminary analysis</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/reprosignals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/reprosignals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproducibility is an important feature of science; experiments are retested, and analyses are repeated. Trust in the findings increases when consistent results are achieved. Despite the importance of reproducibility, significant work is often involved in these efforts, and some published findings may not be reproducible due to oversights or errors. In this paper, we examine a myriad of features in scholarly articles published in computer science conferences and journals and test how they correlate with reproducibility. We collected data from three different sources that labeled publications as either reproducible or irreproducible and employed statistical significance tests to identify features of those publications that hold clues about reproducibility. We found the readability of the scholarly article and accessibility of the software artifacts through hyperlinks to be strong signals noticeable amongst reproducible scholarly articles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laying Foundations to Quantify the “Effort of Reproducibility”</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/effortly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/effortly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are some research studies easy to reproduce while others are difficult? Casting doubt on the accuracy of scientific work is not fruitful, especially when an individual researcher cannot reproduce the claims made in the paper. There could be many subjective reasons behind the inability to reproduce a scientific paper. The field of Machine Learning (ML) faces a reproducibility crisis, and surveying a portion of published articles has resulted in a group realization that although sharing code repositories would be appreciable, code bases are not the end all be all for determining the reproducibility of an article. Various parties involved in the publication process have come forward to address the reproducibility crisis and solutions such as badging articles as reproducible, reproducibility checklists at conferences (NeurIPS, ICML, ICLR, etc.), and sharing artifacts on OpenReview come across as promising solutions to the core problem. The breadth of literature on reproducibility focuses on measures required to avoid ir-reproducibility, and there is not much research into the effort behind reproducing these articles. In this paper, we investigate the factors that contribute to the easiness and difficulty of reproducing previously published studies and report on the foundational framework to quantify effort of reproducibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Survey on Representation Learning based Graph Dimensionality Reduction Techniques</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/graphreprlearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/graphreprlearning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dimensionality reduction techniques map data represented on higher dimensions onto lower dimensions with varying degrees of information loss. Graph dimensionality reduction techniques adopt the same principle of providing latent representations of the graph structure with minor adaptations to the output representations along with the input data. There exist several cutting edge techniques that are efficient at generating embeddings from graph data and projecting them onto low dimensional latent spaces. Due to variations in the operational philosophy, the benefits of a particular graph dimensionality reduction technique might not prove advantageous to every scenario or rather every dataset. As a result, some techniques are efficient at representing the relationship between nodes at lower dimensions, while others are good at encapsulating the entire graph structure on low dimensional space. We present this survey to outline the benefits as well as problems associated with the existing graph dimensionality reduction techniques. We also attempted to connect the dots regarding the potential improvements to some of the techniques. This survey could be helpful for upcoming researchers interested in exploring the usage of graph representation learning to effectively produce low-dimensional graph embeddings with varying degrees of granularity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early indicators of scientific impact: Predicting citations with altmetrics</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/scholarlyimpact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/scholarlyimpact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying important scholarly literature at an early stage is vital to the academic research community and other stakeholders such as technology companies and government bodies. Due to the sheer amount of research published and the growth of ever-changing interdisciplinary areas, researchers need an efficient way to identify important scholarly work. The number of citations a given research publication has accrued has been used for this purpose, but these take time to occur and longer to accumulate. In this article, we use altmetrics to predict the short-term and long-term citations that a scholarly publication could receive. We build various classification and regression models and evaluate their performance, finding neural networks and ensemble models to perform best for these tasks. We also find that Mendeley readership is the most important factor in predicting the early citations, followed by other factors such as the academic status of the readers (e.g., student, postdoc, professor), followers on Twitter, online post length, author count, and the number of mentions on Twitter, Wikipedia, and across different countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do we quantify uncertainty in deep learning models ?</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/how-do-we-quantify-uncertainty-in-deep-learning-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/how-do-we-quantify-uncertainty-in-deep-learning-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;neural-networks-everywhere&#34;&gt;Neural Networks Everywhere&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The genesis of Deep Learning began primarily in 2012 when researchers were able to capture the information present in millions of images and accurately predict class labels. This breakthrough was a culmination of multiple scientific developments. Quintessentially, Neural networks are universal functional approximators and this innate quality allows them to applied on diverse problem spaces. This is the fundamental reason behind the pervasive nature of Neural Networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morality - it&#39;s influence on thought and action</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/morality-its-influence-on-thought-and-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/morality-its-influence-on-thought-and-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not a philosopher but I observe the fundamental nature of things in my surroundings. Right from my childhood to this moment when I am orchestrating this article there are countless thoughts that surround my head when my inner self whispers “morality”. My thought process takes quick writhing movements wandering around searching for answers. The reason for me writing this piece is to both look for answers and portray my ethos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The three C&#39;s of Javascript</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/the-three-cs-of-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/the-three-cs-of-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You might be wondering what the three C’s are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Callbacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ok what are those ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I start, let me tell you that in Javascript Functions are Objects. So every object in Javascript, be it Number, String, Array; Every Object in javascript has a prototype object. For instance if the object is declared using an object literal then, it has access to Object.prototype, Similarly all the arrays so declared have access to the Array.prototype. So since functions are objects, they can be used like any other value. They can be stored in variables, objects, and arrays. They can also be passed as arguments to functions, and do not forget that functions can be returned from functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using social media and scholarly text to predict public understanding of science</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/pubundsci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/projects/pubundsci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often struggle to understand scientific texts, which leads to miscommunication and often to inaccurate and even sensationalistic reports of research. Identifying and achieving a better understanding of the factors that affect comprehension would be helpful to analyze what improves public understanding of science. In this study, we generate features from scientific text that represent some common text structures and use them to predict the semantic similarity between the scientific text and the textual content posted by the general public about the same scientific text online. In this endeavor, we built regression models to achieve this purpose and evaluated them based on their R-squared values and mean squared errors. R-squared values as high as 0.73 were observed, indicating a high chance of a relationship between certain textual features and the public&amp;rsquo;s understanding of science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>numgo - ND Array based math library for Go</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/numgo-nd-array-based-math-library-for-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/numgo-nd-array-based-math-library-for-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;numgo---nd-array-based-math-library-for-go&#34;&gt;numgo - ND Array based math library for Go&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathematical computations and statistical operations contribute immensely to the development of machine learning models in diverse disciplines. Arrays are the most frequently used data structure in most of these applications. Basing on this I have thought of porting python’s &lt;strong&gt;numpy&lt;/strong&gt; library to &lt;strong&gt;go-lang.&lt;/strong&gt; The name of the project is  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/akhilpandey95/numgo&#34;&gt;numgo.&lt;/a&gt;  After learning &lt;strong&gt;go-lang&lt;/strong&gt; I always wanted to practically implement something with the knowledge I have gathered. The project therefore, meant a lot to me since It is both a programming excercise and an opportunity to build something in &lt;strong&gt;go-lang.&lt;/strong&gt; As mentioned before, the repository is inspired by numpy for python therefore, most of the concepts and ideas are broadly taken from numpy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pubundsci - An independent research study</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/pubundsci-an-independent-research-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/pubundsci-an-independent-research-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While technological and scientific advancement paved its way in the 20th century giving scope for researchers to publish of a plethora of scientific literature, “Public Understanding of Science” has been at the center stage of discussion among researchers for the past decade. This very concern sprouts from the fact that most of the scientific reportage that occurs on News Media is subject to personal interpretation. Also, the misapprehensions of the scientific findings can cause repercussions of unimaginable scale in the real world.
Let us consider a small use case. For suppose, “ABC” is a research organization that publishes a scientific finding regarding the relationship between pregnancy and theobromine. Now, there might be a news media outlet that picks the same research article and broadcasts the results in a science journalism segment. The problem arises if the findings in the research paper are incorrectly represented by the Media Outlets. If the research finding says “There is a 30% chance of not having a miscarriage during pregnancy if the woman has theobromine in her diet”, the media outlet would report it in the following way, “A recent finding suggests that chocolate is good for your health during pregnancy and it would help you to reduce the chance of a miscarriage”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compatibility for the Web</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/compatibility-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/compatibility-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Webcompat, is one of the recent interests that I find myself occupied with. The community is wonderful and the whole idea of having a place where users can report problems is quite fantastic. I believe that this can evolve as something greater, since webcompat.com is not only a website that focusses on bug reporting and problems, since I believe that it is a common ecosystem where users, developers and site owners are notified with the issues on the web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the GNU/Linux System</title>
      <link>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/tuning-the-gnu/linux-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://akhilpandey95.github.io/blog/tuning-the-gnu/linux-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always used to find myself in a difficult situation when I had to travel and work. The main reason for this is my machine had a GNU/Linux based distro running and I couldn’t stay away from a charging spot for more than two hours. I always was intrigued to explore this segment and solve this very problem in order to better my travel experience.
Basically there are couple of things to be kept in mind before you go out and try the tricks mentioned here, Consider them basics; So they are :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
